Guide to the Thomas Parran Papers, 1892-1968 UA.90.F14
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Thomas Parran Papers
1916-1962
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Parran, Thomas
UA.90.F14
75.94 Linear Feet (139 boxes)
The papers of Thomas Parran consist primarily of material related to his tenure as Surgeon General of the United States, as one of the founders of the World Health Organization, and the first dean of the University of Pittsburgh's Graduate School of Public Health. Dr. Parran served as Surgeon General from 1936-1948. During his career, Dr. Parran worked to eradicate such diseases as tuberculosis, veneral disease, diphtheria, malaria, hookworm and maternal and infant mortality.
Scope and Content Notes
The University Archives accessioned and processed the papers of Dr. Thomas Parran in 1982-1983. The significance of these papers lies in the depth, scope and time frame of the material. The collection spans the years 1916-1962, beginning with Dr. Parran career as a field investigator for the U.S. Public Health Service through his retirement in 1958 as Dean of the University of Pittsburgh's Graduate School of Public Health. The material from 1958-1962 concern various organizations with which Dr. Parran was involved.
In 1930 Dr. Parran met with the Governor of New York, Franklin D. Roosevelt. His association with Roosevelt lead to his career with the Public Health Service and his appointment as Surgeon General of the United States in 1936.
During World War II, Parran's career took on an international perspective as he became involved in world health concerns with the United Nations. He traveled to many parts of the world including the Soviet Union, China, Latin America and eventually to Japan where he studied the effects of radiation caused by the atomic bomb.
In 1948, the Board of Trustees of the University of Pittsburgh successfully recruited Dr. Parran to become Dean of the newly formed Graduate School of Public Health. He served as Dean until 1958.
The papers include some information gathered by Dr. Parran for his numerous publications on venereal disease and public health as well has background material for his highly acclaimed book on venereal disease, Shadow on the Land.
Access Restrictions
Some folders in Series X and XI are marked as Confidential and require access permission from the University Archivist.
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the Archives from Graduate School of Public Health, University of Pittsburgh in 1981.
Previous Citation
Thomas Parran Papers, 1916-1962, UA.90.F14, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
International agencies; United Nations associations; University of Pittsburgh; International cooperation -- Societies, etc.; Faculty papers; Health and medicine; New York (State) -- Medical care; Medicine -- New York (State) -- Societies, etc.; Research institutes -- Illinois -- Chicago; Public health administration -- United States; Public health -- Study and teaching -- Pennsylvania; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania; Public health -- International cooperation; Public health -- United States; Preventive health services; Medicine -- New York (State); Science -- Societies, etc.; Medicine -- Societies, etc.; Radio in health education -- United States; Population; International organization; World health -- Societies, etc.; Public health -- Societies, etc.; Cancer -- United States; Cancer -- Research -- Societies, etc.; Charities -- United States; Vitamins -- Societies, etc; Trade and professional associations -- United States; Nutrition -- Societies, etc.; Research institutes -- Illinois; Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Davis, Michael Marks -- Correspondence; De Kruif, Paul -- Correspondence; Moore, Joseph Earle -- Correspondence; Parran, Thomas; United Nations -- Economic assistance
- Personal Correspondence, 1930-1947; I.
  - Baruch, Bernard (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cornell, Paul Cullen, Thomas S. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Davis, Michael M. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - De Kruif, Paul (1935-1939) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - De Kruif, Paul (1940) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dobos, Druper, Gusack (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Farrand, Livingston (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Folks, Homer (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Jameson, Sir Wilson (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Kemp, Jarold E. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Kennedy, Foster (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Kingsbury, John A. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Leathers, W.S. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Lehman, Hon. Herbert H. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Lumsden, L.L. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - McCormack, A.T. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - McKinney, Roessle (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - McShane, Margaret (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Merck, George W. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Meyer, Eugene (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Miller, Francis P. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Miller, Knox E. and Murray, Vance B. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Moore, Joseph Earle (Box 3, Folder 23a)
  - Moore, Joseph Earle (Box 4, Folder 23b)
  - Mulliken, Otis (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Orr, Sir John (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - The Order of 1606 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Picken, Ralph, M.F., M.B. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Ruhland, George C. (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Schwitalla, Father (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Sebrell - Shimkin - J.S. Simmons - H.F. Smith - Sigerist (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Simpson, Walter (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Spies - Stolz - Surran (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Stokes, John H. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Thomas, Elbert - Thompson, L.R. (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Walton - Warner - West (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Welch, Dr. William H. (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Wenger, O.C. (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - White House (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Wightman - Wile - Williams (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Williams Huntington (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Winslow, C.E.A. (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - France (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Great Britain (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Scandinavian countries (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Foreign (misc.) (Box 5, Folder 46)
- Inactive Office Files, 1930-1939; II.
  - Appraisal forms for rural health work - APHA - American Public Health Association (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - President-elect congratulatory letters, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Financial statements, 1935-1936 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Treasurer's report, 1932 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence in re appointment of Executive Secretary (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - General Correspondence, 1933-1936 (Box 6, Folder 52-55)
  - General Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Minutes, 1933-1938 (Box 7, Folder 57-59)
  - Governing Council, 1935-1941 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Membership Lists, 1935-1938 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Miscellaneous reports, 1933-1935 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Committee for Improvements in Administrative Health and Welfare Services, 1932-1933 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Committee on Essentials of Health Organization, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Committee on Medical Care, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Committee on Stabilization of Public Health Services, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - National Health Council; a report by Ira V. Hiscock, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - APHA Southern and Western Branches, 1936-1937 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - American Social Hygiene Association corresp. and memoranda American Society for the Control of Cancer (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Correspondences, 1932-1936 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Minutes and miscellaneous reports, 1934-1936 (Box 9, Folder 71-73)
  - Minutes and miscellaneous reports, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - American Society for the Control of Cancer Minutes and miscellaneous reports, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Albany City Health Dept., correspondence personal official, 1933-1934 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Albany County Medical Society, 1931-1935 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Allied Sciences of Oklahoma, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - American Young Men correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - American Epidemiological Society, 1934-1935 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - American Association of University Women, 1933-1954 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - American Legion National Child Welfare Executive Committee, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - American Medical Association correspondence, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Annual Conference of Health Officers and Public Health Nurses, Saratoga Springs, N.Y., 1935 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - Associated Grocery Manufacturers of America General correspondence, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Association of Military Surgeons of the United States, 1937-1939 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health Demonstration, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Cancer. Proposed Upstate program, American Society for the Control of Cancer, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Cancer League, International General Correspondence, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Cleveland Child Health Association correspondence, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Children's Bureaus U.S. Labor Dept., 1933 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Children's Council - New York State (follow-up of National White House 1933 Conference on Child Health and Protection), 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 92)
  - Committee on Neighborhood Health Dept. (Dept. of Health New York City - report), 1935 (Box 11, Folder 93)
  - Committee on the Costs of Medical Care Correspondence, reports and memos, 1932-1934 (Box 11, Folder 94)
  - County Health departments campaign committee, 1930-1931 (Box 11, Folder 95)
  - Committee on Economic Security for the President, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 96)
  - Dental Society of the State of New York correspondence, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 97)
  - District State Health Offices Visits by Dr. Brooks and Dr. Godfrey, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 98)
  - Emergency Relief Appropriation Act of 1935 (Federal) (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - Federation of Women's Clubs of New York State correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - Federation of Women's Educational Organizations New York State Health Education Program, 1931 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Flood in New York State the summer of 1935, Memoranda and news releases (Box 12, Folder 102-103)
  - Food and Health Exposition, New York. Correspondence and memoranda, 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - Georgetown Medical School, 1932-1936 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - Greater New York Safety Council, 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - Governor's office, Executive Dept. Correspondence personal official, 1930-1935 (Box 12, Folder 107)
  - Harvard University lectures - correspondence, 1931-1936 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - Illinois Commercial Men's Association, 1927-1936 (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - Industrial Hygiene occupational diseases, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 110)
  - International Conference on Dermatology and Syphilology IX Congress. Report to Secy of State, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Interstate Sanitation Commission New York. Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - League of Nations- Health Section. Visit of Medical Health officers to U.S. general correspondence, Oct. 7 - Dec. 7, 1935 (Box 12, Folder 113)
  - League of Nations- Quarterly bulletin of the Health Organization, Vol. IV, No. 1, March 1935 (Box 12, Folder 114)
  - League of Nations- Miscellaneous correspondence and publication: World Organization Present and Future (Box 12, Folder 115)
  - League of Nations- Health organization - Denmark, Germany, Netherlands, 1924-1926 (Box 12, Folder 116)
  - Letchworth Village (State institution at Thiells, N.Y.), 1934 (Box 13, Folder 117)
  - Life Extension Institute, Inc. correspondence and memoranda, 1932-1937 (Box 13, Folder 118)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology correspondence, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 119)
  - Maternity Center Association of New York City. Correspondence and memoranda, 1931-1935 (Box 13, Folder 120)
  - Medical care and public health, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 121)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York correspondence, 1933-1936 (Box 13, Folder 122)
  - Medical Society of the State of New York Maternal and Child Hygiene Committee, 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 123)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- correspondence, 1931-1937 (Box 13, Folder 124)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- minutes, 1932-1936 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund- reports, 1932-1935 (Box 14, Folder 126-128)
  - National Institute of Health, USPH Service correspondence, 1930-1935 (Box 14, Folder 129)
  - National Industrial Recovery Act, 1933 (Box 14, Folder 130)
  - Parran, Thomas Jr., M.D. news clippings (Box 14, Folder 131)
  - New York State Dept. of Health, summary of annual report, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 132)
  - Next Practical Steps in Public Health in the State of New York, 1934-1935 (Box 14, Folder 133)
  - New York city Director of Health Administration correspondence, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 134)
  - New York State Organization for Public Health Nursing, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 135)
  - Nurses Association, New York State - Trends in Public Health annual convention, Syracuse, N.Y., 1935 (Box 14, Folder 136)
  - Organization of the New York State Department of Health outline, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 137)
  - Planning Council, New York State- General correspondence and the law, 1935-1938 (Box 15, Folder 138)
  - Planning Council, New York State- Law, reports and misc. memoranda, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 139)
  - Planning Council, New York State- General correspondence, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 140)
  - Planning Council, New York State- temporary minutes of meetings (Box 15, Folder 141)
  - Planning Council, New York State- Temporary Committee on Social Trends Dr. Parran chairman, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 142)
  - Planning Council, New York State- temporary organization, membership list, etc (Box 15, Folder 143)
  - Planning Council, New York State- news clippings, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - Planning Council, New York State- Minutes (Box 15, Folder 145)
  - Pneumonia Program of Studies for New York State - Proposed program, memoranda, etc. (Box 16, Folder 146)
  - Pneumonia Program... correspondence, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 147)
  - Public Health Administration (Box 16, Folder 148)
  - Public Health Council. Correspondence, memoranda, personal official, 1930-1934 (Box 16, Folder 149)
  - Parran, Thomas Jr. M.D. Opinion by the Attorney General of the State of New York in re term of office of State Health Commissioner Personal, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 150)
  - Public Health Institute of Chicago- correspondence, memoranda, 1930-1936 (Box 16, Folder 151)
  - Public Health Institute of Chicago- reports, memoranda, news clippings, 1930-1934 (Box 16, Folder 152)
  - Rensselaer County. Proposed health district. Correspondence, memoranda. Official, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 153)
  - Rensselaer County Tuberculosis and Health Association, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 154)
  - Retirement system in New York State correspondence and statements - official. Dr. Parran's retirement, 1930, 1931, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 155)
  - Rockefeller Foundation. Correspondence official, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 156)
  - Roseman, Dr. Milton J. Testimonial in honor of Dr. Roseman in Boston. General correspondence, Nov. 27, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 157)
  - Rural Homes Commission (appointed by Gov. Franklin D. Roosevelt), Sept, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 158)
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund, Julius Rosenwald Fund - Program of Medical Economics (Dr. Davis) (Box 17, Folder 159)
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund, reports, misc. memoranda (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Julius Rosenwald Fund - reports, misc. memoranda (Box 17, Folder 160)
  - Albemarle County, Va. (Rosenwald Fund) (Box 17, Folder 161)
  - Bolivar County (Study) - Rosenwald Fund (Box 17, Folder 162)
  - Glynn County, Ga. (study) Rosenwald Fund. Study by Dr. Parran, et al. (Box 17, Folder 163)
  - Macon County Ala. Rosenwald Fund, Study by Dr. Parran et al. (Box 17, Folder 164)
  - Pitt County, N.C. Rosenwald Fund. Study by Parran et al. (Box 17, Folder 165)
  - Sipton County, Tenn. Rosenwald Fund. Study by Parran et al. (Box 17, Folder 166)
  - General data correspondence Rosenwald Fund. Study by Parran et al. (Box 17, Folder 167)
  - Salaries. Correspondence with Budget Director of the state, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 168)
  - Federal emergency Relief Administration. Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Box 17, Folder 169)
  - Reorganization - medical societies, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 170)
  - Federal Government Reorganization- The plan and charts, Health, Education Welfare Services, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 171)
  - Federal Government Reorganization- general correspondence, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 172)
  - 'S' Miscellaneous and general correspondence (Box 18, Folder 173)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- Expense accounts, official forms, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 174)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- Agenda for meetings of board, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 175)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- Correspondence, General, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 176)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- reports, memoranda (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- organization, membership, 1934-1935 (Box 18, Folder 178)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- report to the President of the United States, 1935 (Box 18, Folder 179)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- minutes of meetings of the board, 1934-1935 (Box 19, Folder 180)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- committee on medical and public health, correspondence official, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 181)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- reports, memoranda re: the board, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 182)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- A report to the President from the board, subject: A national program for putting science to work for the national welfare, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 183)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- possibilities of dev. mineral industries tributary to Boulder Dam, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 184)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- committee on mapping services of the federal government, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 185)
  - Science Advisory Board: National- committee on mapping services, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 186)
  - Social Security Law, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 187)
  - Science Advisory Board- correspondence, general, official, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 188)
  - Science Advisory Board- committee on medicine and public health, 1935 (Box 20, Folder 189)
  - Social Security Law - reports, memoranda 1935 (Box 20, Folder 190)
  - Social Security Committee - general correspondence, 1934-35 (Box 20, Folder 191)
  - Social Security Committee - (Economic Security) history - executive order, 1934-35 (Box 20, Folder 192)
  - Social Security Law - correspondence, 1934-35 (Box 20, Folder 193)
  - Social Security Committee Sub-Committee on Child Welfare - children's bureau, U.S. Labor Department, 1934-35 (Box 20, Folder 194)
  - Sub-committee's Correspondence, 1934-35 (Box 21, Folder 195)
  - Social Insurance Against Illness, abstract of a program, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 196)
  - Social Security Committee - National - Reports, memoranda, misc., 1934-35 (Box 21, Folder 197)
  - State Charities Aid Association - General Correspondence, General Correspondence, 1932-34 (Box 21, Folder 198)
  - State Charities Aid Association - General Correspondence, Reports, misc., 1929-1931 (Box 21, Folder 199)
  - State and provisional health authorities of North America - correspondence, related memoranda, 1932-34 (Box 21, Folder 200)
  - Syracuse University - Commencement, 1934 (Box 21, Folder 201)
  - Scarlet Fever Serum - NY, 1932-36 (Box 21, Folder 202)
  - Tax Laws, Commission for Revision of Mostick Commission, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 203)
  - Temporary Emergency Relief Administration, law - free milk, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 204)
  - Temporary Emergency Relief Administration, New York state - food allowance standards in upstate welfare districts, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - Temporary Emergency Relief Administration, Medical relief program in the state of New York, 1932-33 (Box 22, Folder 206)
  - Temporary Emergency Relief Administration, Sickness census tables and related data, 1932-33 (Box 22, Folder 207)
  - Tennessee State Dept. of Health - Manual for the Conduct of County Health Depts, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 208)
  - Ten Year Construction Program Estimate - New York State, 1931 (Box 22, Folder 209)
  - Tuberculosis Control Program, Buffalo, 1934 (Box 22, Folder 210)
  - Tuberculosis activities - Survey in New York City by Spec. Commission, 1933 (Box 22, Folder 211)
  - Employment Relief - bond issue in the state of New York, 1933-1935 (Box 22, Folder 212)
  - U.S. Bureau of the Census, Dept. of Commerce. Correspondence, list of officials, etc., 1935 (Box 22, Folder 213)
  - U.S.P.H. Service, Missouri - Tri-State Sanitary District, 1920-21 (Box 23, Folder 214)
  - U.S.P.H. Service- Montana sanitary survey, 1920 (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - U.S.P.H. Service- Muscle Shoals Sanitary Survey, 1918-19 (Box 23, Folder 216)
  - United States Veteran's Hospital Project, 1933-1934 (Box 23, Folder 217)
  - U.S.P.H.S. Correspondence, official, 1934, 1935 (Box 23, Folder 218-219)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- U.S.P.H.S. Minutes, 1931 (Box 23, Folder 220)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Misc. Correponsence with U.S.P.H.S., 1930-33 (Box 23, Folder 221)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Misc. Correponsence with U.S.P.H.S., 1934 (Box 24, Folder 222)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Misc. Correponsence with U.S.P.H.S., 1935 (Box 24, Folder 223)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Manuscripts, con't misc., 1932-35 (Box 24, Folder 224)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Organization of Committee on Research in Syphilis, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 225)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Report to the Executive Committee on Research in Syphilis, 1929 (Box 24, Folder 226)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies Correspondence- Cole, Dr. Harold N. (Box 24, Folder 227)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies Correspondence- Moore, Dr. J. Earle (Box 24, Folder 228)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies Correspondence- O'Leary, Dr. Paul A. (Box 24, Folder 229)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies Correspondence- Stokes, Dr. John H. (Box 24, Folder 230)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Nile, Dr. Aldo J. (Box 25, Folder 231)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Copenhagen paper manuscript, correspondence, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 232)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Cole, Dr. Harold N. - application for grant, Western Reserve University, 1928-32 (Box 25, Folder 233)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Moore, Dr. Joseph Earle - application for grant, Johns Hopkins University, 1928-32 (Box 25, Folder 234)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- O'Leary, Dr. Paul A. - application for grant, The Mayo Clinic, 1928-32 (Box 25, Folder 235)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Stokes, Dr. John H. - application for grant, University of Pennsylvania, 1928-32 (Box 25, Folder 236)
  - U.S. Cooperating Clinical Syphilis Studies- Nile, Dr. Aldo J. - application for grant, University of Michigan, 1928-32 (Box 25, Folder 237)
  - United States Public Health Service - correspondence official, 1930-33 (Box 25, Folder 238)
  - United States and Surgeon General - letters of endorsement from health officers, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 239)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection- General correspondence, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 240)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection- Hoover's address, 1930-31 (Box 26, Folder 241)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection- Correspondence re: federal health legislation, 1930-31 (Box 26, Folder 242)
  - Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation - general correspondence, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 243)
  - Women Employees in executive or similar positions in the Dept. and Health, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 244)
- Congratulatory Letters, 1926-1944; III.
  - Letters A-H (Box 26, Folder 245-252)
  - Letters I-Z (Box 27, Folder 253-262)
- Publications - Correspondence, Travel Expenses, Vouchers, 1926-1944; IV.
  - Personal - miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 263)
  - Mendal Medal, Villanova College, Pa. (Box 27, Folder 264)